# Contact

+420 731 647 707 (Mobile) Product.Success@Nik.Page

www.linkedin.com/in/nbpage (LinkedIn) nik.page (Company)

# Top Skills

Leadership
Product Management
Innovation Consulting

# Languages

Czech (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

# Certifications

Google for Startups Facilitator / Mentor

Google Design Sprint Master

#### Honors-Awards

Google Developer Expert: Product & UX

# **Publications**

The Interface is Not the Experience Getting to Happy

Baby Boomers: Adoption of Fintech Among the Hesitant

UX Strategy – It Is All About The Experience

# Nik Page

Design Thinking Applied \* UX Driven Product Design \* Google for Startups Mentor \* Startup Fanatic Since 1979

**United States** 

# Summary

Experience, in the the commercial sphere is the sum of emotions a person feels while interacting with your brand. That person can be an employee, a supplier, an investor, or a customer. The experience is built on the relationships with those people.

Experience strategy should take into account your brand position, product design and delivery, and marketing.

Leave it all to chance or gain control of the experience your company provides.

Your choice.

# Experience

Nik Page Experience Strategy & Design

Product Creator & Experience Designer, Innovation Leader, Consultant, Coach

August 2016 - Present (8 years 8 months)

Praha

Services offered in product or experience:

- \* Understand: Who is IT for and why should they care?
- \* Innovate: Find or invent potential experience or product solutions.
- \* Verify: Test the concepts to find the experience with the best market fit.
- \* Build: Lead and inspire the team to get from design to reality.

#### Innovation:

- \* Brainstorm new approaches, methods, or desired outcomes
- \* Plan steps to get there
- \* Identify metrics to assess success of innovation
- \* Refine, Build & Scale

I do the above or help a team build the competency to take it in-house.

Public Speaking / Lecturing

Public Speaker & Promoter, Customer/User Experience : Experience Design

2013 - Present (12 years)

@ Your Next Conference

I enjoy promoting Experience by Design and am happy to speak at your event.

- Dev Challenge XIX, Judge in Product Design, Lodz, Poland 2022
- Quantum Technologies and Their Use for the Armed Forces, Prague 2019
- ⇒ Panel Discussion
- Artificial Intelligence in Military IoT Applications, Prague 2019
- ⇒ Panel Discussion
- Blockchain for Humanity, Amsterdam 2019
- ⇒ Designing Experience in Social Impact Startups
- Coalition 4 Good, Geneva 2019
- ⇒ UX in Crypto
- Google Launchpad, Budapest 2018
- ⇒ Experience Design for Startups
- Dezentrum, Zurich 2018
- ⇒ User Experience in dApps
- ENS Domains Hackathon, London 2018
- ⇒ UX Mentor
- Design Thinking Summit, Berlin 2018
- ⇒ Conference Chair
- ⇒ Experimental Design Sprint 1 hr with 100 Participants
- DAPP (DAPPs Adoption Paralelni Polis), Prague 2018
- ⇒ Experience Design in Blockchain: Current Status
- BlockStars The Business of Blockchain, Prague 2018
- ⇒ Experience Design in Blockchain: Mass Adoption
- Design Thinking Summit, Prague 2017

- ⇒ Conference Chair
- ⇒ UX Strategy: Be an Experience Provider The ROI benefit
- Google Developer Group DevFest, Budapest 2017
- ⇒ UX Strategy: Why & How
- Google Developer Group DevFest, Voronezh 2017
- ⇒ The UX of VR / AR
- Czech VR Fest, Prague 2017
- ⇒ Round Table Discussion
- Web Expo, Prague 2016
- ⇒ The Business Side of Experience Strategy
- Charles University, Prague
- ⇒ Experience Design in Corporate Culture
- Web Expo Prague 2015
- ⇒ Results Driven UX Prototyping & User Testing
- ⇒ API DX: The Developer Experience
- University of Economics, Prague (VŠE) 2015
- ⇒ Agile & UX
- Customer Experience Association 2015
- ⇒ Iterative Design as a way of building Customer-Centric philosophy
- UX Konference 2014
- ⇒ UX Tools Review
- Web Expo Prague 2014
- ⇒ Invisible Intelligent Ubiquitous Banking
- UX Konference Prague 2013
- ⇒ Bringing UX into Corporate Culture
- UX Masterclass Prague 2013
- ⇒ Building UX Competency

- WebExpo Prague 2013
- ⇒ Emergent Service Design

# Salsita Software

Sr Product & Account Manager

November 2022 - October 2023 (1 year)

Prague, Czechia

- \* Leading multiple product development projects for start-ups and accounts such as eBay.
- \* Product discovery, solution design.
- \* Managing multiple project teams concurrently.

### wflow.com

Head of Product Research & Design

January 2022 - October 2022 (10 months)

Prague, Czechia

Developing market intelligence methods. Innovating product design. Building out Product Management & Design processes.

# Blockchain4Humanity

**Experience Positioning Advisor** 

January 2019 - July 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Advise on Experience & Product Design Strategy.

This includes understanding donor motivations, web, app & other channel design, prototyping & testing experience models.

## Aerum Official

**Executive Strategy Advisor** 

June 2018 - June 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

- \* Experience & Business Developments strategy.
- \* User-Focused Product Management

# **BLOCKS**

Advisor: Experience Strategy

May 2018 - November 2018 (7 months)

Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

Developing the Experience Strategy for the company launch.

Advising top management on brand, communications, media campaign, products design.

Blocks is a service that will connect institutional investors with unique and professionally selected real estate opportunities worldwide using blockchain and crypto technologies to bring far greater flexibility to investors while reducing costs and speeding up the process 10's of Billions of EUR on the exchange by 2020.

Faculty of Arts, Charles University in Prague Visiting Lecturer February 2017 - June 2017 (5 months) Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

Leading a for credit course covering strategic experience planning from product inception to sunset.

Česká spořitelna (Czech Savings Bank)
3 years 11 months

Head of Experience Design
July 2014 - August 2016 (2 years 2 months)
Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

Building the Experience Design team carry out prototyping, testing, overall user centric design. Created the sense of need for UX within a broad section of the company. Fostered growth in UX Maturity.

Evangelize Experience by Design within the company, promote greater understanding of the benefits and methodologies in the business and product teams.

Lead exploration of new approaches and methodologies such as API UX (Developer Experience, DX), Lean UX in a corporate environment, gamification of User Testing, and Big Data analysis as an exploration UX tool.

UX Team Founder October 2012 - July 2014 (1 year 10 months)

Created a need for UX services and a small team to meet them.

Lecture on UX practice and principals

Instigate tools, toys and and activities to promote UC / CX / UCD

Coach & Consult with Dev, Business, Project Management and others

ČSOB (Czechoslovak Commercial Bank) Managing Consultant August 2011 - October 2011 (3 months)

Page 5 of 8

Launched new Testing Team within this 3.5 Billion Kč project. Managed team of Testing Analyst Leads. Wrote Test Strategy and Charter. Managed budget and capacity planning. Handed off to an operational manager.

## Airbank

Managing Consultant January 2011 - March 2011 (3 months)

Member of a small leadership team leading QA analysts, developing QA strategy and process and liaising with the client. The project is the setting up of a new bank from the ground up.

## **AVG**

Manager, QA Labs
March 2010 - December 2010 (10 months)

Manage two teams, one team of QA Analysts and one team of Test Automation Engineers.

Report to higher management on release, process and other risks and develop mitigation plans.

Help drive R&D into new testing methodologies and processes including n-wise and progression.

Assess headcount, education, infrastructure needs for for upcoming fiscal year and juggle budget for current one.

# **ZOOM International**

Manager QA and UX

November 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 2 months)

Recommend and Manage process changes including issues reporting workflow, communication with Support, Product Management and Development teams

Formalize product development process with focus on QA - Transitioning to TMMi model

Manage team with reporting and hire / fire and bonus level responsibility Develop User studies to help inform new product development

Monster Worldwide
User Researcher & UX Team Lead
February 2003 - March 2008 (5 years 2 months)
UX Team, New Product Group
Lead large, multinational user studies
Participated in focus group studies

Conducted 1 on 1 user studies

Evangelized multivariate and other automated user behavior testing
Task and traffic managed UX team's work
Participated in new product planning

European Initiatives Team, Web Services Group
Lead a small but diverse team of 7
Managed multiple projects and assigned tasks
Responsible for hiring, motivation, performance review, salary
Internal client relations

Morgan Stanley Online Sr. QA Engineer March 2000 - January 2001 (11 months)

Instrumental in lobbying for and developing ownership, communications and documentation process for large international analysis, develop and QA teams. Developed standards and templates for test plans, bug reporting, and change requests. Developed and managed test lab. Wrote and implemented test plans. Conducted and documented ambiguity reviews of technical specifications and business requirements documents.

Wells Fargo Quality Assurance Consultant January 2000 - June 2000 (6 months)

Developed new QA reporting process for Online Advertising team. Wrote and implemented test plans. Conducted and documented Ambiguity review on product development documents including Business Requirements and Technical Specifications.

## **EDP**

Consultant 1997 - 2000 (3 years)

Contract QA Consulting. Clients included:

Pacific Bell

Canon

Prompt Software QA Guy 1995 - 1997 (2 years) Designed QA process Wrote and implemented test plans

Managed Beta test efforts

Evangelized usability & product design innovations

Software Toolworks Quality Assurance Engineer 1993 - 1995 (2 years)

Testing of games, piano and typing tutors, and infotainment packages. Evangelizing for design changes based on usability.

# Education

Computing Learning Center Informatics, Mainframe Programming · (1992 - 1994)